Inventory of O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period O.41
O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period
- List of Jews from Zeitz Elster and their fate during the Holocaust, date empty; The file was created by Jens Aaron Guttstein; 84 List of murdered Jews List of Jewish survivors List of Jewish residents File; O.41/1299
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Jens Aaron Guttstein
  List of Jews from Zeitz Elster and their fate during the Holocaust
  The list/s contain approximately 259 names
- List of Jews from Poliske and settlements in the Poliske vicinity who were murdered, 1941-1943, Список евреiв - жертв окупантiв у роки Великоi Вiтчизняноi вiйни Полiський район Киiвськоi областi; 20/05/2009-20/05/2009; The file was created by הקהילה היהודית ב-Brovary; 11 List of murdered Jews xerox; O.41/1335
  Mass burial; Memorials; Poliske,Kaganovich,Kiev,Ukraine (USSR); Maksimovichi,Kaganovich,Kiev,Ukraine (USSR); <>,Kaganovich,Kiev,Ukraine (USSR); Vovchkiv,Rozvazhev,Kiev,Ukraine (USSR); Zalyshany,Rozvazhev,Kiev,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by David Turovsky
  List of Jews from Poliske and settlements in the Poliske vicinity who were murdered, 1941-1943
  The list/s contain approximately 262 names
- List of Jews from Hungary who were inmates in Natzweiler camp, 27 September 1944, 27/09/1944-27/09/1944; The file was created by SS-Standortfuehrung Mittelbau, Politische Abteilung; 9 List of camp inmates xerox; O.41/1308
  Jewish prisoners; Hungarian Jews; Natzweiler,Camp; <>,<>,<>,Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by George Stein
  List of Jews from Hungary who were inmates in Natzweiler camp, 27 September 1944
  The list/s contain approximately 243 names
- Documentation regarding Bockfield and Skweres family members who perished during the Holocaust, 22/07/1942-20/01/1944; 36 Official documentation List of deportees Personal documents xerox; O.41/1312
  Polish Jews - Deportations; Transports; Drancy,Camp,France; Praszka,Wielun,Lodz,Poland; Pajeczno,Radomsko,Lodz,Poland; Warsaw,Warszawa,Warszawa,Poland; Strassburg,Bas Rhin,<>,France; Paris,Seine,<>,France; Lodz,Ghetto,Poland; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Transport from Drancy,Camp,France to Auschwitz Birkenau,Extermination Camp,Poland; Deportations to Auschwitz
  The material was aquired by Yad Vashem from CENTRE DE DOCUMENTATION JUIVE CONTEMPORAINE, PARIS, FRANCE
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Ruth Cohen
  Documentation regarding Bockfield and Skweres family members who perished during the Holocaust Documents include deportation lists, inmates cards, an official letter sent from Paris by an SS officer regarding a deportation of Jews to Auschwitz, with explanations about transports from Drancy to Auschwitz that included Bockfield family members (including the names of children on transport no. 66).
- List of Jews from Hungary who perished in a camp in Dorosics, Ukraine, 1943, date empty; 26 List of murdered persons Article Personal documents Original and Xerox Original Typewriting; O.41/1317
  Hungarian Jews - Extermination; Military forced labor battalions; Mass burial; Killing of Jews by Hungarians; Dorosics,Korosten,Zhitomir,Ukraine (USSR)
  The material was aquired by Yad Vashem from Hadtörténeti Intézet és Múzeum Hadtörténelmi Levéltára, Budapest, Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by יוסי וייס
  List of Jews from Hungary who perished in a camp in Dorosics, Ukraine, 1943 The file includes: About the murder of Jews in Dorosics, from the Erec periodical; Personal document of Mendel Weisz, grandfather of the submitter of the material, who perished in the camp, from the Hadtorteneti Intezet es Muzeum card catalog.
  - List of 396 Jews from Hungary who perished in a camp in Dorosics, Ukraine, 1943, date empty; 8 List of murdered persons List of Hungarian labor battalion victims; O.41/1317.1
    Dorosics,Korosten,Zhitomir,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of 396 Jews from Hungary who perished in a camp in Dorosics, Ukraine, 1943
    The list/s contain approximately 396 names
- List of 97 names of people who perished and of survivors, from Hungary, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland and Romania, taken from 11 books, 2009-2009; The file was created by רחל בן-אליעזר; 12 List of murdered Jews List of Jewish survivors File; O.41/1304
  <>,<>,<>,Poland; <>,<>,<>,The Netherlands; <>,<>,<>,Germany; <>,<>,<>,Hungary; <>,<>,<>,Romania
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by רחל בן-אליעזר
  List of 97 names of people who perished and of survivors, from Hungary, Germany, the Netherlands, Poland and Romania, taken from 11 books The names of the books are: 1. "Let Us Not Forget" by Irene Teger; 2. "My Turbulent Life" by Arthur M. Ingster; 3. "Oma's True Story (The Story of My Life)" by Rose de Liema; 4. "Survival from Nazi Persecution" by Marie Rebhun; 5. "Our Journey in the Valley of Tears" by Andrzej and Karolina Jus; 6. "Middle Andzia" by Anda Meisels Rosen; 7. "My Darkest Years" by James Bachner; 8. "The First Morning Light" by Yaakov Barzilai; 9. "My Star" by Felicja Nowak; 10. "Live, Remember, Tell the World" by Leah Kaufman and Sheina Medwed; 11. "From Kletsk to Siberia" by Alter Pekier.
- List of perished, prepared by Rabbi Abraham Israel Jacobson in Stockholm or in DP camps, 1945-1946, 1945-1946; 46 List of murdered Jews Handwritten; O.41/1337
  "She’erith Hapletah"; Perished; Stockholm,<>,<>,Sweden; <>,<>,<>,Sweden
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by צמח יעקובסון
  List of perished, prepared by Rabbi Abraham Israel Jacobson in Stockholm or in DP camps, 1945-1946
  The list/s contain approximately 397 names
- List of 69 Jews from Stopnica who perished during the Holocaust, 02/1994-19/04/1994; The file was created by שושנה רוזן; 4 List of murdered Jews xerox; O.41/1341
  Stopnica,Busko,Kielce,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by נאוה כהן
  List of 69 Jews from Stopnica who perished during the Holocaust
- Section of a list of Jews deported from Hamburg, 11/07/1942, 10/07/1942-10/07/1942; The file was created by גסטפו; 3 List of deportees File; O.41/1346
  Expulsion from Germany; Hamburg,Hamburg,Hamburg,Germany; Transport to Auschwitz,<>,<>,<>
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Gad Hofmann
  Section of a list of Jews deported from Hamburg, 11/07/1942 The deportees include the grandfather and family members of the submitter of the material, the Hofmann family.
- List of 1,425 Jews from various places who perished during the Holocaust, prepared by their family members, members of the Jewish community in Göteborg, Sweden, 11/2009-11/2009; The file was created by הקהילה היהודית; 41 List of murdered Jews Newspaper clippings Official documentation Original Typewriting Original; O.41/1321
  Memorials; Memorial sites; Goteborg,<>,<>,Sweden
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Boris Aptekman
  List of 1,425 Jews from various places who perished during the Holocaust, prepared by their family members, members of the Jewish community in Göteborg, Sweden Information regarding the establishment of a memorial site by the local Jewish community.
  - List of 1,425 Jews from various places who perished during the Holocaust, prepared by their family members, members of the Jewish community in Göteborg, Sweden, Список имен погибших в годы войны 1941-1945 гг., написанных на памятных монументах на площадке перед синагогой еврейской общины г. Гетеборга; 11/2009-11/2009; 14 List of murdered Jews; O.41/1321.1
    Memorials; Goteborg,<>,<>,Sweden
    List of 1,425 Jews from various places who perished during the Holocaust, prepared by their family members, members of the Jewish community in Göteborg, Sweden
    The list/s contain approximately 1425 names
- List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from the Kalinindorf district who died in battle at the front, 15/09/2007-20/02/2010; The file was created by Vladimir Lummer; 55 List of murdered Jews List of Jewish soldiers List of Jewish survivors Newspaper clippings Letter of testimony Handwritten, original Original and Xerox; O.41/1353
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Commemoration; Mass burial; Memorials; Holocaust survivors; Kalinindorf,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR); Bobrovy Kut,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR); Shterndorf,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR); <>,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ולדימיר לומר
  List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from the Kalinindorf district who died in battle at the front The file includes newspaper clippings on the subject of the Holocaust in the Kalinindorf district and a letter of testimony from Vladimir Lummer that includes names of survivors from the Kalinindorf area.
  - List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from the Kalinindorf district who died in battle at the front, date empty; 43 List of murdered Jews List of Jewish soldiers; O.41/1353.1
    Kalinindorf,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR); Shterndorf,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR); Bobrovy Kut,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR); <>,Kalinindorf,Nikolayev,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from the Kalinindorf district who died in battle at the front
- Yizkor book of the Jewish community of Zawiercie, including names of the Jews who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; The file was created by ארגון יוצאי Zawiercie והסביבה; 24 List of murdered Jews Yizkor book Photograph Original; O.41/1328
  Commemoration; Bequeathing the Holocaust; Zawiercie,Zawiercie,Kielce,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ליבר מושקוביץ
  Yizkor book of the Jewish community of Zawiercie, including names of the Jews who perished during the Holocaust
- List of Jews from various places in Ukraine who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; The file was created by Holocaust Center and Foundation; 10 List of murdered Jews File; O.41/1333
  <>,<>,<>,Ukraine (USSR)
  List of Jews from various places in Ukraine who perished during the Holocaust
- List of Jews murdered in the Euthanasia Program ("Aktion" T4) in Pirna-Sonnenstein, 1940-1941, Jewish victims of the "euthanasia" killing center Pirna-Sonnenstein 1940/1941; date empty; The file was created by Julius Scharnetzky; 11 List of murdered Jews xerox; O.41/1350
  Euthanasia; Aktion 14f13; Keywords for visual sources; Gas chambers; Mentally Ill people; Sonnenstein,Camp,Germany; Buchenwald,Camp; Sachsenhausen,Camp,Germany; Aktion T4
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Julius Scharnetzky
  List of Jews murdered in the Euthanasia Program ("Aktion" T4) in Pirna-Sonnenstein, 1940-1941 Murder of mentally ill and disabled patients who were in local convalescent homes (sanatorium); transfer of inmates from Buchenwald and Sachsenhausen to Pirna-Sonnenstein in order to murder them in the context of the Euthanasia Program.
- List of Jews from the Vilna region and Odessa who were murdered, prepared by Lara Giber, date empty; The file was created by ראיסה שטוטמן; 2 List of murdered Jews Original; O.41/1291
  Molodechno,Molodeczno,Wilno,Poland; Smorgon,Oszmiana,Wilno,Poland; Vileyka,Wilejka,Wilno,Poland; Odessa,Odessa City,Odessa,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ראיסה שטוטמן
  List of Jews from the Vilna region and Odessa who were murdered, prepared by Lara Giber
- List of 610 Jews from Bistrita and settlements in the Bistrita vicinity who perished in Auschwitz, 1944-1945, date empty; The file was created by הקהילה היהודית ב-Bistrita; 13 List of murdered Jews xerox; O.41/1296
  Deportation from Romania; Bistrita,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Nimigea de Jos,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Nimigea de Sus,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Rebra,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Dorolea,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Saratel,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Magherus,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Ilva Mare,Nasaud,Transylvania,Romania; Transport to Auschwitz,<>,<>,<>
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Fredi Deac
  List of 610 Jews from Bistrita and settlements in the Bistrita vicinity who perished in Auschwitz, 1944-1945
- List of Jews designated for deportation from Hannover, Germany to Riga, 15/12/1941, date empty; The file was created by Deutsch-Israelische Gesellschaft; 5 List of deportees xerox; O.41/1300
  Hannover,Hannover,Hanover,Germany; Riga,Camp; Transport from Hannover,Hannover,Hanover,Germany to Riga,Ghetto on 15/12/1941
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מלי זונאבנד
  List of Jews designated for deportation from Hannover, Germany to Riga, 15/12/1941
  The list/s contain approximately 1001 names
- List of Jews, Koenig family members, who were murdered by the Nazis, summer 1942, date empty; The file was created by Shmuel Koenig; 3 List of murdered Jews xerox; O.41/1287
  Murder of family and acquaintances; Mielnica,Borszczow,Tarnopol,Poland; Murder of the Mielnica Jews in a Jewish cemetery, 1942-1944
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מרגלית כץ
  List of Jews, Koenig family members, who were murdered by the Nazis, summer 1942
- Genealogic documentation of the Turfrijer family from Amsterdam, from 1743, including the names of the family members who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; The file was created by Michel Koppe; 18 Genealogy Record of murdered persons Printout File; O.41/1309
  Dutch Jews; Amsterdam,Noordholland,<>,The Netherlands; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Sobibor,Extermination Camp,Poland; Bergen Belsen,Camp,Germany
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Michel Koppe
  Genealogic documentation of the Turfrijer family from Amsterdam, from 1743, including the names of the family members who perished during the Holocaust
- Diagram of Bransk, Poland, 1932, including delineation of borders of the Jewish quarter and location of synagogues; list of 82 Jewish families who were residents in Bransk, 1932, date empty; 4 Diagram List of Jewish residents xerox; O.41/1313
  Synagogues before the war; Polish Jews; Bransk,Bielsk Podlaski,Bialystok,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Ed Baker
  Diagram of Bransk, Poland, 1932, including delineation of borders of the Jewish quarter and location of synagogues; list of 82 Jewish families who were residents in Bransk, 1932
  - List of 82 Jewish families who were residents of Bransk, 1932, date empty; 1 List of Jewish residents; O.41/1313.1
    List of 82 Jewish families who were residents of Bransk, 1932
- List of Jews from Poland who were detained in Le Vernet camp, 1941-1944, date empty; The file was created by Jan Laury; 8 List of camp inmates File; O.41/1318
  Jewish prisoners; Le Vernet,Camp,France; <>,<>,<>,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Jan Laury
  List of Jews from Poland who were detained in Le Vernet camp, 1941-1944
- List of 161 Jews from Regensburg deported to Piaski, Auschwitz or Theresienstadt, date empty; The file was created by משטרה; 11 List of deportees xerox; O.41/1305
  German Jews - Deportation; Regensburg,Niederbayern und Oberpfalz,Bavaria,Germany; Piaski,Camp; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Theresienstadt,Ghetto,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by יוספה וינר לב עמי
  List of 161 Jews from Regensburg deported to Piaski, Auschwitz or Theresienstadt
  The list/s contain approximately 161 names
- List of Jews from Balta who perished in the Balta Ghetto or died in battle during their service as Red Army soldiers, 1941-1944, 2009-2009; The file was created by Pavel Kozlenko; 28 List of murdered Jews List of Jewish soldiers xerox; O.41/1338
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Balta,Balta,Moldaviya ASSR,Ukraine (USSR); Balta,Ghetto,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by יוסף שולמן
  List of Jews from Balta who perished in the Balta Ghetto or died in battle during their service as Red Army soldiers, 1941-1944
  The list/s contain approximately 798 names
- List of 35 Jews from Honci János Street in Uzhorod, who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; The file was created by אדית אנגלמן; 3 List of murdered Jews Original; O.41/1342
  Uzhorod,Uzhorod,Carpathian Ruthenia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אדית אנגלמן
  List of 35 Jews from Honci János Street in Uzhorod, who perished during the Holocaust
- List of 92 Jews from Ksiaz Wielki and registry of 1,781 marriages and births in Grabowiec, 1920-1938, 1920-1938; 96 List of Jewish residents xerox; O.41/1343
  Jews listings; Polish Jews; Jewish communities; Ksiaz Wielki,Miechow,Kielce,Poland; Grabowiec,Hrubieszow,Lublin,Poland; Grabowiec,<>,<>,Poland; Hrubieszow,Hrubieszow,Lublin,Poland; Miechow,Miechow,Kielce,Poland; Bilgoraj,Bilgoraj,Lublin,Poland
  List of 92 Jews from Ksiaz Wielki and registry of 1,781 marriages and births in Grabowiec, 1920-1938 List of Jews from Ksiaz Wielki based on the birth registry data, 1936; registry of marriages and births in Grabowiec, 1920-1938.
  - List of Jewish residents of Ksiaz Wielki, based on data from the birth registry, 1936, 1936-1936; 4 List of Jewish residents; O.41/1343.1
    Ksiaz Wielki,Miechow,Kielce,Poland
    List of Jewish residents of Ksiaz Wielki, based on data from the birth registry, 1936
  - List of Jews from Grabowiec who married between 1920-1938, 1920-1938; 23 List of Jewish residents; O.41/1343.2
    Grabowiec,Hrubieszow,Lublin,Poland
    List of Jews from Grabowiec who married between 1920-1938
    The list/s contain approximately 327 names
  - List of Jews from Grabowiec who were born between 1920-1938, 1920-1938; 63 List of Jewish residents List of children; O.41/1343.3
    List of Jews from Grabowiec who were born between 1920-1938
    The list/s contain approximately 1283 names
- Section from a list of Jews from the Muenster district deported to the Theresienstadt Ghetto and the Warsaw Ghetto, 1942, and their fate, Vierter Transport vom 31. Juli 1942 von Münster und Bielefeld nach Theresienstadt (Transport XI/1 der Stapo(leit)stelle Münster und Bielefeld); Dritter Transport vom 31. März 1942 über Hannover nach Warschau; date empty; 8 List of deportees File; O.41/1347
  Expulsion from Germany; Deportation to Poland; <>,Muenster,Westphalia,Germany; Warszawa,Ghetto; Theresienstadt,Ghetto,Czechoslovakia; Transport to Theresienstadt,Litomerice,Bohemia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אורי קלט
  Section from a list of Jews from the Muenster district deported to the Theresienstadt Ghetto and the Warsaw Ghetto, 1942, and their fate
- List of 25 Jews from Hungary and Ukraine; most of them were murdered in Auschwitz, date empty; The file was created by אוה שץ; 3 List of murdered Jews Original Typewritten original; O.41/1322
  <>,<>,<>,Hungary; <>,<>,<>,Ukraine (USSR); Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by דני נימרי
  List of 25 Jews from Hungary and Ukraine; most of them were murdered in Auschwitz
- Diagram of Kudirkos Naumiestis, Lithuania, from the period before the war, including names of Jewish residents who resided in Kudirkos Naumiestis, date empty; 2 Diagram List of residents Handwritten, original; O.41/1354
  Lithuanian Jews; Kudirkos Naumiestis,Sakiai,<>,Lithuania
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Elizabet Zborowski
  Diagram of Kudirkos Naumiestis, Lithuania, from the period before the war, including names of Jewish residents who resided in Kudirkos Naumiestis
- List of Jews from Kupiskis, Lithuania, who perished during the Holocaust; list prepared, 1946, 1946-1946; 17 List of murdered Jews xerox; O.41/1292
  Lithuanian Jews; Mass murders; Kupiskis,Panevezys,<>,Lithuania; Panevezys,Panevezys,<>,Lithuania
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by פיי מוריס
  List of Jews from Kupiskis, Lithuania, who perished during the Holocaust; list prepared, 1946 - List prepared by the midwife in the Jewish hospital in Ponevezh, 1946; information regarding the circumstances of the death of Jachilevitch family members, whose names appear on the list.
- Survey from a history book about the Krasnopolye district, regarding the murder of Jews, 1941-1942, 11/01/1990-2001; 14 Survey List of murdered persons List of Jewish soldiers Original; O.41/1329
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; <>,Krasnopolye,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR); Krasnopolye Area,Sovkhoz Kalinina,Soviet farm,Murder Site,Belorussia (USSR); Krasnopolye Area,cemetery,Murder Site,Belorussia (USSR); Krasnopolye,Krasnopolye,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR); Shooting of the Krasnopolye Jews in an anti-tank ditch near the municipal cemetery, 20 November 1941; Shooting of the Krasnopolye Jews in the vicinity of the Kalinin sovkhoz, October 1941
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Vladimir Rubinstein
  Survey from a history book about the Krasnopolye district, regarding the murder of Jews, 1941-1942
  - List of Jews from Krasnopolye who were repressed by the Soviet authorities, 1933-1938, Возвращенные имена (о репрессированных евреях); 11/01/1990-2001; 2 List of detainees; O.41/1329.1
    Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Krasnopolye,Krasnopolye,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR); Shooting of the Krasnopolye Jews in an anti-tank ditch near the municipal cemetery, 20 November 1941; Shooting of the Krasnopolye Jews in the vicinity of the Kalinin sovkhoz, October 1941
    List of Jews from Krasnopolye who were repressed by the Soviet authorities, 1933-1938
  - List of Jewish soldiers from Krasnopolye who died in battle at the front, 1941-1945, Воины Красной Армии, погибшие при освобождении Краснополья и похоронены на его территории. Воины-земляки, погибшие и пропавшие без вести на фронтах Великой Отечественной войны в 1941-1945 гг.; 11/01/1990-2001; 4 List of Jewish soldiers; O.41/1329.2
    Krasnopolye,Krasnopolye,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jewish soldiers from Krasnopolye who died in battle at the front, 1941-1945
  - List of Jews from Krasnopolye who were murdered, 1941-1942, Жертвы фашизма: мирные граждане - жители района, замученные оккупантами; 11/01/1990-2001; 3 List of murdered Jews; O.41/1329.3
    List of Jews from Krasnopolye who were murdered, 1941-1942
- List of Jews from Sarmas who were murdered by the Nazis and buried in the local cemetery, 09/1944, Tablou nominal al evreilor masacrati de hoardele maghiare in comuna Sarmas; 21/02/1945-21/02/1945; The file was created by Federatia Uniunilor de Comunitati Evreesti; 4 List of murdered Jews Photograph xerox Printout; O.41/1387
  Sarmas,Cluj,Transylvania,Romania; Massacre in Sarmas, Transylvania, 17 September 1944
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שמואל פדר
  List of Jews from Sarmas who were murdered by the Nazis and buried in the local cemetery, 09/1944
  The list/s contain approximately 126 names
- List of Jews from Bobruysk who perished during the Holocaust and Jewish Red Army soldiers who died in battle in the Bobruysk area, date empty; The file was created by Jewish History and Culture Museum of Belarus; 66 List of murdered Jews List of Jewish soldiers List of Jewish partisans File; O.41/1374
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Partisans - Jews; Bobruysk,Bobruysk City,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Inna Gerasimova
  List of Jews from Bobruysk who perished during the Holocaust and Jewish Red Army soldiers who died in battle in the Bobruysk area
  The list/s contain approximately 2129 names
- Personal documentation of Johanna Rosenthal, her husband Jacob Rosenthal and their daughter Ingeborg, 08/10/1936-; 31 Passport Questionnaire Certification Official documentation Death certificate Personal documents Handwritten, original Original Typewriting Original and Xerox; O.41/1378